Harry Wang-Ul

Senior Web Developer - AngularJs

Princeton, NJ - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Harry-Wang-UI/f6499e4271de8cc3

About 7 years of experience in front-end web development and web-based application design. Extensive experience of current web standards (W3C) hands-on coding of HTML 4.0/5.0, XHTML, CSS/CSS3, JavaScript, ¡Query, AngularJS, NodeJs, KnockoutJs, React, Bootstrap, C#, Python, MySQL.

- Hands-on experience in designing and developing webpage and user interface (UI) using HTML, SASS/CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery and AngularJS.
- Strong knowledge and rich experience in Core Java and Python.
- Experience in handling RESTful Web Service and rendering the data in web application using JQuery and AngularJS along with JSON parsing to render the response data to user interface.
- Strong knowledge on Single Page Application (SPA) using AngularJS framework, and hands-on experience MVC design patterns and various JavaScript Frameworks.
- Expertise in styling webpage layouts using CSS/CSS3 concepts along with Media Queries and CSS Bootstrap.
- Experience on debugging and troubleshooting using Chrome Inspector, Firebug and IE Tester. Version control tools using GIT, expertise in Jasmine for unit testing.
- Solved complicated Cross-Browser compatibility issues on various browser Safari, Chrome, Firefox, Internet Explorer.
- Experienced in responsive web design.
- Strong experience on AJAX techniques for manipulating and parsing multiple data types including JSON and XML.
- Having very good experience using Scaffolding tools like Bower and Grunt.
- Solid concept of all phases of software development life cycles (SDLC) and hands on experience with NodesJs server application, Firebase, MongoDB, good understanding of interfaces with back Oracle and SQL.
- Outstanding experience in multiple IDEs such as Eclipse, Notepad++, WebStorm, Plunker.
- Excellent communication skills, strong sense of responsibility, quick learner in new environment, an innovative team player.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Web Developer

AngularJs - Redmond, WA - February 2016 to Present

Responsibilities:

- Responsible for user interface design, implementing responsive websites using JavaScript, JQuery, AngularJs, Knockout.js, Typescript, CSS/CSS3, HTML5.
- Have good experience on developing SPA and JQuery based web developing under Typescript.
- Have rich experience for UX related bug fixing under MVVM(Angular.js) framework.
- Experienced in developing SPA elements under MVVM(Angular.js) framework including time zone selector and system message center.
- Developed incident search & summary widget for monitoring system using JQuery and Knockout.js.
- Experienced in building C# controller for routing, async tasks like authorization adding, and data fetching.
- Used GIT and Visual Studio Team Foundation Server for version control.
- Have experience in working with different teams for short-term project.

• Worked on wrapping up and user feedback such as maintenance of the content and improving the user experience.

Environment: C#, JavaScript, HTML5, HTML, CSS3, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Angular.js, Knockout.js, Typescript, JSON, DOM, AJAX, Agile, RESTful Web Service, GIT

Senior Web Developer

Capital One - Arlington, VA - May 2014 to February 2016

Responsibilities:

- Use HTML, CSS/CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, JQuery and AngularJS for web designing.
- Utilize AngularJS creating client-side Single Page Application (SPA) and to validate user input.
- Create External Style Sheets to web pages using SASS, LASS, CSS and Bootstrap.
- Perform a custom animation of a set of CSS properties using jQuery.
- Implement new Cross-Browser accessible interfaces using Bootstrap, JavaScript and CSS.
- · Work closely with securing additional resource for the team and also worked in GIT Environment.
- Construct websocket server with Node.js and JavaScript.
- Create different modules with specific controllers, templates, scopes, custom filters and directives using AngularJS.
- Involved in the developing functions to acquire data from the APIs using AJAX to implement more efficient client facing applications.
- Handle browser compatibility issues with different browsers related to HTML, CSS and JavaScript for Chrome,
 IE, and Firefox.
- Perform JSON data parsing using AngularJS to render the information on user interface pages.
- Perform debugging and troubleshooting code using Chrome Inspector.
- Cooperate with team members to conduct user research with strong communication, analytical and interpersonal skills.

Environment: Java 6, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, AJAX, JQuery, JSON, AngularJS, CSS Bootstrap, Agile, REST API, Chrome Inspector, Firebug, GIT

Senior Web Developer

Suntrust Bank - Atlanta, GA - January 2013 to April 2014

Responsibilities:

- Responsible for user interface design, implementing responsive websites using JavaScript, JQuery, JQuery UI, Bootstrap, CSS/CSS3, HTML5.
- Used Bootstrap to develop UI with responsive design.
- Developed PDF, EXCEL and print previews for all the reports in the application using HTML plugin.
- Utilized JQuery and AJAX on form design and user input validation.
- Used JavaScript and jQuery to generate dynamic web pages.
- Built webpage include stock trade course picture, video using CSS3 style sheet and Bootstrap.
- Implement feature like Animate Scroll full screen editor easy drop down Using JQuery Plugin.
- Used JQuery to navigate to different pages of application and create AJAX to handle asynchronous communication between client and server.
- Developed course video search system using JQuery with YouTube search APIs and implemented efficient paper search on Scottrade database.
- Used GIT for version control.
- Participated in debugging using Jasmine, Firebug and Chrome Inspector.
- Worked on website maintenance such as updating the content and improving the user experience.

Environment: Java 6, JavaScript, HTML5, HTML, CSS3, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, JSON, DOM, AJAX, Bootstrap, Agile, RESTful Web Service, GIT

UI developer

LevelUp - Boston, MA - March 2012 to January 2013

Responsibilities:

- Developed user interface using JavaScript, Ajax, JQuery, HTML5 and CSS/CSS3.
- Produced page contents using Media Query responsive layout design to fit different devices.
- Implemented input validation using JQuery and navigated to different pages of the application and create AJAX to handle asynchronous communication between client and server.
- Used CSS and HTML for website layout and design.
- Designed business applications using web technologies like HTML, DHTML, XHTML, XSL, XSLT and CSS based on the W3C standards.
- Developed highly user interactive web pages with HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Worked closely with QA team to fix bugs with Firebug and IE Tester.
- Handled all aspects of the web application including maintain, testing, debugging and deploying.
- Worked with the business analysts and back-end developers to gather requirements, improve application functionality and add new features.
- Drafted weekly report for the team and also worked on GIT environment.

Environment: Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, XML, XHTML, JQuery, JSON, AJAX, GIT

UI developer

Verizon - Waltham, MA - October 2010 to March 2012

Responsibilities:

- Developed the front-end using HTML, JavaScript, and AJAX.
- Implemented the validation form by JavaScript and jQuery.
- Created master pages, CSS Styles Sheets and Integrated to Silver light and got approval from Business Stake holders.
- Used JQuery Plugins for Drag and Drop Widgets, menus, user Interface and Forms.
- Used SVN to version control and updated application version and committed to repository change.
- Created a responsive website that fits all users and devices from desktop and mobile phone using Media Queries.

Environment: Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, XML, AJAX, MYSQL, SVN

UI developer - Internship

University Federal Credit Union - Austin, TX - May 2010 to August 2010

Responsibilities:

- Worked closely with application development team to improve the user experience of the internal applications, performed the front-end development using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and JQuery.
- Fetched data from API/web services via AJAX-JSON calls and displayed them.
- Implemented JavaScript for the expression validation.
- Worked on website maintenance such as updating the content and solving different bug reports.
- Tested and improved the cross-browser compatibility on all major browsers.

Environment: Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, JQuery, AJAX, JSON

EDUCATION

B.S in computer science

University of Texas at Austin - Austin, TX

Tools Google Web Toolkit, Eclipse, WebStorm, Plunker

SKILLS

CSS (7 years), HTML (7 years), JAVASCRIPT (7 years), jQuery (7 years), JAVA (5 years)

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Skills Summary

General Programming Language C, C++, Java, C#, Python
Scripting Language JavaScript, JQuery, React, Knockout.js and UNIX shell scripting
Web Programming Language HTML, HTML5, CSS, CSS3
Web Server / XML Apache TOMCAT / DOM, XSD, XML.
Framework Bootstrap, AngularJS
Database Oracle, SQL Server, MySQL, PL/SQL